<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>fiskeren.github.io</title>
    <link>https://fiskeren.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on fiskeren.github.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 17:28:43 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fiskeren.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Geolocating IP addresses in Velociraptor</title>
      <link>https://fiskeren.github.io/posts/velogeoip/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 17:28:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fiskeren.github.io/posts/velogeoip/</guid>
      <description>I read the blog post by Carlos Cajigas and saw his YouTube video demonstrating some really neat Velociraptor tricks including usage of the build in geoip() function, which can be used to enrich artefacts in Velociraptor hunts. This inspired me to write this small blog post where I&amp;rsquo;ll quickly run over how to use geoip().
This could be useful if you for example know hosts normally only connects to IPs located in the US, Ireland and UK and want to spot that specific process that connects to something else, or if you are on the lookout for processes connecting to hosts in a specific country etc - insert your own use case :-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Velociraptor Threathunting - Quick Introduction</title>
      <link>https://fiskeren.github.io/posts/velothreathunt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 11:30:36 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fiskeren.github.io/posts/velothreathunt/</guid>
      <description>In my previous posts I&amp;rsquo;ve shown how to use Velociraptor to extract artefacts from dead hosts, but the real strength of Velociraptor is in its capability to do searches across multiple hosts for artefacts. This is really useful when responders are trying to determine the questions such as &amp;ldquo;Are there baddies in the network?&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;How many machines have executable X on it?&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Did user X log on to system Y?&amp;rdquo; etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Standalone Artifact Collector</title>
      <link>https://fiskeren.github.io/posts/creating_collector/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 16:30:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fiskeren.github.io/posts/creating_collector/</guid>
      <description>I got quite a few positive reactions to my last post about how to do deadhost collections, so I thought I wanted to follow it up with another post about how to create a standalone collector that can collect artefacts from a running host using Velociraptor.
Velociraptor is an awesome DFIR tool made to efficiently get visibility into endpoints. It can be run in a server/agent setup, essentially working as an EDR with thousands of hosts, and it can also be used as a standalone artefact collector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://fiskeren.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 13:42:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fiskeren.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, my name is Asger Strunk. I work as an incident reponder in the UK. I&amp;rsquo;ve made this small blog just for a place to publish some of the stuff I&amp;rsquo;m tinkering with.
For contact, please go to my LinkedIn</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deadhost Investigation and Super Timeline</title>
      <link>https://fiskeren.github.io/posts/deadhostinvestigation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 09:45:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fiskeren.github.io/posts/deadhostinvestigation/</guid>
      <description>I recently attended a SANS 508 course and got time to play around with Velociraptor, which is an awesome DFIR tool made to efficiently get visibility into endpoints. It can be run in a server/agent setup, essentially working as an EDR with thousands of hosts, and it can also be used as a standalone artifact collector.
In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll try to explain how to use the Velociraptor executable as a artefact collector to quickly collect Windows artefacts from a dead host image.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
