<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>fiskeren.github.io</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on fiskeren.github.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 15:50:44 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Geolocating IP addresses in Velociraptor</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/velogeoip/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 17:28:43 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/velogeoip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I read the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mashthatkey.com/2022/08/velociraptor-playground-2022-08-02.html?m=1&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; by Carlos Cajigas and saw his &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DMj0pU6kYvg&#34;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; video demonstrating some really neat Velociraptor tricks including usage of the build in &lt;code&gt;geoip()&lt;/code&gt; function, which can be used to enrich artefacts in Velociraptor hunts. This inspired me to write this small blog post where I&amp;rsquo;ll quickly run over how to use &lt;code&gt;geoip()&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This could be useful if you for example know hosts normally only connects to IPs located in the US, Ireland and UK and want to spot that specific process that connects to something else, or if you are on the lookout for processes connecting to hosts in a specific country etc - insert your own use case :-)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Velociraptor Threathunting - Quick Introduction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/velothreathunt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 11:30:36 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/velothreathunt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my previous posts, I demonstrated how to use Velociraptor to extract artefacts from dead hosts. However, the real strength of Velociraptor lies in its ability to conduct searches across multiple hosts for artefacts. This is particularly useful when responders are trying to answer questions such as, &amp;ldquo;Are there baddies in the network?&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;How many machines have executable X on them?&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Did user X log on to system Y?&amp;rdquo; In this blog post, I will provide a quick introduction to using Velociraptor to address these types of questions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating Standalone Artifact Collector</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/creating_collector/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 16:30:11 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/creating_collector/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I received several positive reactions to my last post about how to perform dead host collections. Therefore, I wanted to follow it up with another post on how to create a standalone collector that can gather artefacts from a running host using Velociraptor.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.velociraptor.app/&#34;&gt;Velociraptor&lt;/a&gt; is an excellent DFIR tool designed to efficiently provide visibility into endpoints. It can operate in a server-agent setup, functioning essentially as an EDR—without the AV, of course—with thousands of hosts. Additionally, it can also serve as a standalone artefact collector.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 13:42:59 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi, my name is Asger Strunk. I am your average Dane working as an incident responder in Munich, Germany. I&amp;rsquo;ve created this small blog as a place to publish some of the things I&amp;rsquo;m tinkering with.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Social media:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/asgerstrunk/&#34;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/hackerkartellet&#34;&gt;X / Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bsky.app/profile/hackerkartellet.bsky.social&#34;&gt;Bsky&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deadhost Investigation and Super Timeline</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/deadhostinvestigation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 09:45:02 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/deadhostinvestigation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently attended a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sans.org/cyber-security-courses/advanced-incident-response-threat-hunting-training/&#34;&gt;SANS 508&lt;/a&gt; course and got time to play around with &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.velociraptor.app/&#34;&gt;Velociraptor&lt;/a&gt;, which is an awesome DFIR tool made to efficiently get visibility into endpoints. It can be run in a server/agent setup, essentially working as an EDR with thousands of hosts, and it can also be used as a standalone artifact collector.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll try to explain how to use the Velociraptor executable as a artefact collector to quickly collect Windows artefacts from a dead host image. After collecting the artefacts, I will show how to create a super timeline using &lt;a href=&#34;https://plaso.readthedocs.io/en/latest/sources/user/Using-log2timeline.html&#34;&gt;Plaso log2timeline&lt;/a&gt; from the evidence collected.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
